"The railway that got the world on track."
“让世界步入正轨的铁路。”
On the 27 September 1825, crowds gathered in a small market town in north-east England to witness something that had not been seen before – a train carrying passengers for the first time.
1825年9月27日，人群聚集在英格兰东北部的一座小型集镇，见证了前所未有的创举——一列火车首次搭载乘客出行。
It had taken eight hours to travel 48km – around the speed of an average cyclist – but this steam locomotive was a pioneer in the development of modern railways and changed the world forever as rail spread across the globe.
它耗时8小时行驶48公里，时速与普通骑行者大致相当，但这台蒸汽机车是现代铁路发展的先驱，随着铁路在全球范围内普及，它永久地改变了世界。
2025 marks 200 years of passenger trains, and the UK is celebrating this milestone with Railway 200 – a year-long programme of events.
2025年是客运列车问世200周年，英国正通过“铁路200”系列活动庆祝这一里程碑，这是一项为期一整年的活动计划。
From guided walking tours along old, abandoned rail routes, to competitions and careers events.
活动包括沿老旧废弃铁路线开展的有向导徒步游览、各类竞赛以及职业招聘会。
Railway 200 organisers have also designed a travelling exhibition on a special train that will criss-cross the UK for 12 months.
“铁路200”的组织者还在一列专列上设计了巡回展览，这列火车将在英国全境穿梭行驶12个月。
Admission to the train is free and there are four carriages, each with a different theme.
列车免费参观，共设有四节车厢，每节车厢主题各不相同。
These include a carriage with hands-on, interactive activities which invite people to test their engineering skills.
其中一节车厢设有亲身体验的互动活动，邀请人们测试自身的工程技能。
Emma Roberts, Railway 200 organiser, said it is an "unforgettable experience" for visitors.
“铁路200”的组织者艾玛·罗伯茨表示，这对游客而言是一场“难忘的体验”。
Also celebrating this bicentennial is Tom Chesshyre, train enthusiast and author of 'Slow Trains Around Britain'.
同样在庆祝这二百周年纪念的还有汤姆·切希尔，他是火车爱好者，也是《环英慢火车之旅》一书的作者。
Among what attracts him to train travel is that you can see places off the beaten track out the train window, and you can relax and read a book without worrying about traffic jams.
火车旅行吸引他的一点在于，能透过车窗看到人迹罕至的地方，还能放松身心阅读书籍，无需担心交通拥堵。
Tom's favourite slow train ride is from Inverness, in the middle of Scotland, to the most northerly station in the whole of the UK in Thurso through "a kind of desolate landscape".
汤姆最喜爱的慢火车线路是从苏格兰中部的因弗内斯，前往英国全境最北端的瑟索车站，沿途会经过“一片荒凉的景致”。
Tom says, "You feel like you're taking a train and disappearing from modern life, leaving it behind."
汤姆说：“你会感觉自己乘着火车，远离了现代生活。”
The route Tom crowned 'most picturesque' was a short journey from St Erth in Cornwall to St Ives which travels along a clifftop with the beach down below.
被汤姆誉为“风景最美”的线路，是从康沃尔郡的圣埃尔赫到圣艾夫斯的短途旅程，列车沿着悬崖顶端行驶，下方就是海滩。
Train travel has come a long way since 1825.
自1825年以来，火车旅行已然取得了长足发展。
Today, trains are more efficient and better connected than ever.
如今，火车比以往任何时候都更高效、连通性也更好。
From the Eurostar, which connects London to mainland Europe through a tunnel under the English Channel, to high-speed routes in Japan and China, the world is on the move.
从穿过英吉利海峡海底隧道，连接伦敦与欧洲大陆的欧洲之星列车，到日本、中国的高铁线路，整个世界都在飞速运转。